# Rahmat Satyawan

## **Electronics Instrument | Health Safety Officer | Web Developer**

satyawan.rahmat@gmail.com | 0821 8283 2166 | LinkedIn/rahmat-satyawan | bit.ly/rahmatst

#### **SUMMARY**

A generalist with 2+ years of experience in nuclear safety in many industries. Enthusiastic and generalist highly-interest about nuclear electronics instrument and safety, automation industry and technology. A tech enthusiast now learning and seeks a career switch in tech industry.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PT. Inosoft-Sinergi Peta Sejahtera

## Bootcamp Front End Developer-VueJS

(Dec 2022 - Mar 2023)

- Learning HTML/CSS/VueJs
- Learning CSS Bootstrap and Tailwind
- Learning Vuex and Vue Router
- Involve in Final Project use Laravel VueJs

### **PROA React - Teknoblox**

#### PROA Digitalent-Kominfo

(Mei 2022 - Aug 2022)

- Learning HTML/CSS/ReactJs
- Learning JavaScript Fundamental
- Learning React State Management

### PT. Java Experts Indonesia

## Intern Front End ReactJS

(Apr 2022 – Jun 2022)

- · Has good knowledge and skills in HTML, CSS
- Involve build dashboard project use ReactJS,
- Involve daily planning and task use Trello

## PT. Thai NDT Indonesia-Kep.Riau

Radiation Safety Officer

(Aug 2021 – Jan 2022)

- Conduct safety and supervise safety radiation
- Conduct daily measurement radiation in storage and site
- Conduct paperwork and site safety for radiation, such us Permit, JSA, PPE and Emergency Tools
- Involve preparing and fulfillment document for Monthly Internal Audit by PT Saipem

## PT. SMS for Astra Infra Port - Kalimantan Timur

## Radiation Safety Officer & HSE Support

(Jul 2020 – Apr 2021)

- Conduct safety and supervise safety radiation
- Conduct daily measurement radiation in storage for MPFM Module
- Conduct HSE Support act as HSE Officer in site and office such as HSE Induction, PTW Register, HSE Inspection and others

## PT. Russindo Expertiza Inspekciya - Riau

## Radiation Safety Officer & Engineer Inspector NDT

(Nov 2018 – Nov 2019)

- Conduct safety and supervise safety radiation
- Perform, Evaluation and Reporting NDT (MT, PT, RT, UT)
- Act as Project Admin at site to maintain work standards, timelines and budget
- Research and developed DJI Drone for UT inspection
- Prepare Product Development Division such as, proposals, cost estimates, specifications etc.

### PT. Badak NGL - Kalimantan Timur

## Internship at Instrument Maintenance Dept.

(Jul 2017 – Sep 2017)

- Conduct root cause analysis for accident fail trip system at cooling water
- Participate to performing preventive maintenance and routine inspections
- Participate to performing turn around maintenance
- Participate to conduct testing and maintenance on DCS and PLC

## **SKILLS**

#### General Skill

- Office Software (Microsoft Office, Trello, Meeting Software, Google Workspace)
- Organization and Communication skill
- Teamwork and communication skill

- Business and Product Development skill
- Analytical thinking and always learning
- Dedicated to completion of tasks in a timely manner and with regard to quality.

### Electronics Instrument Skill

- Microcontroller (Zilog, ATmega, Arduino)
- Conduct Automation (PLC, DCS Yokogawa, LabVIEW)
- Instrumentation (Proteus, Altium Designer, MATLAB, Cisco Packet Tracer)
- Programming Language (Arduino, C#, Delphi, Visual Basic, JS)
- Software Graphic Design (Photoshop, CorelDraw)
- Basic CAD (AutoCAD, SolidWorks, Sketchup)
- Development product of DJI Drone Matrice for Inspection
- NDT Inspection (MT, PT, RT, UT, FLIR IR)
- Instrumentation Tools (Oscilloscope, Signal Generator, Power Supply, Megger Test etc.)
- Analysis and troubleshooting of A/D electronic systems

## Health Safety Skill

- Nuclear Instrumentations (SCA&MCA, XRF, Gamma Camera, X-ray etc.)
- Radiation Safety Officer and HSE Awareness
- Risk Assessment and Emergency Response
- · Safety regulations and compliance
- Incident Investigation and Safety Culture

## Web Developer Skill

- Programming Language (Arduino, C#, Delphi, Visual Basic, HTML&CSS)
- Bootstrap, Tailwind
- ReactJS, VueJS
- NodeJS, PHP,
- MySQL, NoSQL
- Git, GitHub, GitLab
- Consume API use Axios

## **EDUCATION**

### Sekolah Tinggi Teknologi Nuklir - (GPA 3.63 0f 4.00)

Bachelor's degree (S.ST)

(Sep 2014 – Aug 2018)

D-IV Nuclear Physics Engineering – Electronics Instrumentation

Final Project: "The Design of 2in1 Geiger Muller and Single Channel Analyzer based on Arduino"

### **ORGANIZATION**

**HIMA Elins STTN** 

Member of Internal Division	(Feb 2016 - Feb 2017)
BEM STTN	, ,
Member of PSDM Department	(Feb 2015 – Feb 2016)

### TRAINING AND CERTIFICATE

React Js Web Frontend -Jabar Coding Camp	
Jabar Coding Camp	(Apr 2022) (No Exp date)
Managing Safely - IOSH	
TWI Middle East	(Apr 2022) (No Exp date)
K3 Umum – Kemnaker RI	

PJ3K PT IMP (Jul 2021) (No Exp date)

Radiation Safety Officer – Industry Level I

<u>Bapeten</u> (Jul 2021 – Jul 2024)

MT & PT NDT Level II

<u>PT Russindo - ASNT</u> (Dec 2018 – Dec 2023)